Hey, what's up guys?
It's Persch. I hope everybody's doing great
and I wanted to bring you guys a little something new.
So I decided I'm gonna do a timeline breakdown for you guys.
I'll be going over my entire process of creating a trailer.
So we will be talking a lot about video editing in this
video, which excites me too much.
Anyways, so this was a podcast that John produces weekly
and we wanted to do a trailer for this.
We did not end up using this trailer.
But anyways, this should give you a pretty good perspective
on what the process looks like.
What are the things that I'm looking for?
How to create a story from a one hour long podcast.
And if you guys have a webinar
or a masterclass, if your client has a webinar
or a masterclass and you want to promote it in ads,
and the only raw footage you have to work with is a webinar,
it can be one hour or two hours long, doesn't matter.
But the point of this video is going to be
how do you go from such large amounts of footage
to something that makes sense, something that has a story,
something that will bring in more people through the door.
I'm gonna play it for you guys,
and breaking down how I got to this.
When you think of all the things in life we do
to make ourselves feel the best, I can't think of anything
that makes me feel as renewed as just sleeping.
I was extremely sleep deprived.
My grades started to go down, my health started to decline.
I was getting sick more often.
It was impossible to try to balance it all.
My body cannot function the same way My digestive
system shuts down altogether.
The brain fog, the fatigue, irritability, attitude,
perspective, communication skills,
all of it goes out the window.
It's literally punishment. Why are we punishing ourselves
by depriving ourselves of sleep?
Totally our deepest loved people in our lives. Mm-hmm.
And yet they can oftentimes get the
weaker sides of ourselves.
Sleep is everything. It's such a foundational piece
of our functioning as humans.
Go take a nap. Go, go,
Go sleep.
Yeah, so that's about it.
So first I'll show you what I had to work with
and how I ended up having this story.
So the raw footage I had was just this 52
minute long podcast.
And the first stage in the process looked something like,
I went through the entire podcast listening,
and every time I, something caught my eye
or I was like, oh, maybe I can use this for the trailer.
I was just cutting it and labeling it.
So if you cut something on Premier Pro
and you right click on it, you go to label,
you can change the color for it, like so.
And this was the entire process of just going
through the footage, seeing what you have to work with.
And I was just labeling everything that I felt like could be
of use hair.
I wasn't too strict. And I labeled it depending on, oh,
maybe the green, all the things
that I labeled green can be used for hooks.
Maybe all the things I labeled as pink can be used
for the premise of the story.
Maybe all of the things that I marked in rose
or red color could be the conflict in the story.
And so then I created a new timeline
where I brought everything
so I can look at everything I cut in one place,
so it was still five minutes,
and I wanted to create a podcast trailer
that was under one minute.
So I went through it again
and I decided to delete some things.
I decided to chop some things more to make it
as concise as possible.
So I created another timeline where I deleted some stuff.
And in your workflow, this is a really important thing
to create new sequences for everything.
So you can always go back.
So in this sequence, I deleted some stuff
and I made sure that I only have what is the most effective,
like the best pieces of content I could find.
But I still had two minutes of footage.
So at this point I started to build out my trailer.
So what I usually do is I stack my timelines like so,
and let's say this was an empty timeline.
I would just go through this
and I was like, oh, maybe I can use this for the hook.
So I would just bring in here, bring it in here. Like so.
And I would start to build out my timeline,
have some sort of a story.
So now I will be going over what structure do I follow
and how do I make the story.
So in a trailer, usually the structure goes something like
you need a cold open or a hook.
So, and the requirements for a hook is it needs to be shot,
it needs to be entertaining,
and it should require little to no context.
Then you have two to three acts.
So the first act can be the premise of the story.
What are we talking about?
The second act can be the conflict in the story.
What are the pain points in the story?
And the third act can be a climax in the story.
And then at the end, you can have a button
or a last tease to keep people watching.
Like you, you can put in some part of an information
or some part of content,
but to know the full piece of information from this content,
you need to watch the entire thing.
So this keeps people watching.
So for the hook, I found out this piece of information
that I thought was, oh, it's short, it's entertaining.
It requires no context,
but it still introduces our story. So
When you think of all the things in life we do
to make ourselves feel the best, I can't think of anything
that makes me feel as renewed as just sleeping.
So instantly with just five seconds of the trailer,
you already know what are they going to be talking about?
It's sleep and it just opens the story to the viewer.
And then after I went to the pain points, I wanted something
that the viewer can relate to.
I wanted to introduce a conflict in the story.
What is the problem that we are facing?
So I ended up choosing this.
I was extremely sleep
Deprived. My grades
started to go down, my health started to decline.
I was getting sick more often.
It was impossible to try to balance it all.
My body cannot function the same way my digestive
system shuts down altogether.
The brain fog, the fatigue, irritability, attitude,
perspective, communication skills, all
of it goes out the window.
So these were, this was the conflict in the story.
All of the things she was facing,
if she wasn't sleeping properly,
this is the conflict in the story.
This is relatable to the viewer
and this encourages them
to keep watching more for the solution.
And then I wanted to have some sort of a pattern interrupt.
Like at this point, they know
what we are talking about from the hook.
They know what the problem they're facing.
And now I wanted to wanted, I wanted the viewer to feel
emotions of, oh, why are we facing this?
I wanted them to be curious. So I found out this,
It's literally punishment.
Why are we punishing ourselves
by depriving ourselves of sleep?
Totally. So I ended up using this,
this invokes curiosity in the viewer.
And then after this I, I wanted something
to escalate more on the conflict.
I wanted to really agitate the pain point more.
So I wanted to have something that is, oh,
if you don't watch this video, if you don't sleep well,
you can have the worst case scenario possible.
Our deepest loved people in our lives,
and yet they can oftentimes get the
weaker sides of ourselves.
Sleep is everything. So this was the
escalation on the conflict.
It is really emotional.
And it was showing the viewer that, oh,
if you don't get this right, the deepest,
the people you love, the deepest in your life can oftentimes
get the weakest version of yourself.
Like this is really agitating the pain point more.
And now all I was left was I needed a conclusion
or a climax in the story.
So I ended up choosing this.
It's such a foundational piece
of our functioning as humans.
So really simple
that o sleep is such a foundational piece in
your functioning as humans.
And then as I said that in the end, this is kind
of optional, but I like to do this is
to in include a last tease to,
and this one, you don't need to give context.
It needs to be that encourages the viewer
to keep watching more to find the solution for this.
We don't want to put all the information in the
trailer itself, of course.
So I wanted to have one last tease
before they get to the full podcast.
Go take a nap, go. Yeah, I'll go sleep.
And I also wanted to include this last tease
because I did not want
to end the trailer on an emotional note.
I wanted it to be more uplifting, more hopeful,
more inspiring at the end so that the viewer keeps watching.
So this was the structure for my trailer.
And now I'll break down the editing for you guys.
So as I said, I put the structure together first
and then I started to do the music.
And if you notice these two tracks,
these are my music tracks.
All these tracks are my sound effects.
And in just a 45 second trailer,
I changed the music four times.
So I started with some epic music buildup, music,
and I put the drop at when she finishes saying her sentence,
When you think of all the things in life we do
to make ourselves feel the best, I can't think of anything
that makes me feel as renewed as just sleeping.
So this was the first buildup music,
and I found all of the music on invato elements.
And the second music is still buildup music.
It's agitating the pain point more.
I was extremely sleep deprived.
My grades started to go down, my health started to decline.
I was getting sick more often.
It was impossible to try to balance it all.
My body cannot function the same way My digestive system
shuts down altogether.
The brain fog, the fatigue, irritability, attitude,
perspective, communication skills,
all of it goes out the window.
It's literally punishment.
Why are we punishing ourselves
by depriving ourselves of sleep?
Totally. So up until the pattern interrupt,
I was using the same buildup music again.
It's still epic music.
It's still what is gonna like the music emotionally.
It gives you the feeling of
what is happening, what is going on.
It's still building up.
And then after the pattern interrupt, when I wanted
to escalate more on the conflict, I decided
to use emotional music.
Because what she says is something really emotional.
I wanted the viewer to feel, uh, really sad at this point.
And if you look at the whole trailer from a bigger
perspective, it's a big emotional rollercoaster.
Our deepest loved people in our lives. Mm-hmm.
And yet they can oftentimes get the
weaker sides of ourselves.
Sleep is everything. It's such a foundational piece.
So I was using emotional music here
and at the end, as I said, I wanted the trailer
to be more hopeful, more inspiring.
I wanted to uplift a more, uplift it a little bit more.
So that's exactly the music I'm using.
It's hopeful, it's inspiring, it's uplifting.
And it continues with the last tease
Piece of our functioning as humans. Go take a nap, go,
Go sleep.
And if I go over the sound effects,
it's just basically a lot of risers.
All of these risers you can find in the
Aza Direct sound effects pack.
So if I play it real quick here,
basically I'm using risers everywhere.
I feel like she's seeing an important point and she ends.
I am using multiple different ones.
I'm overlaying it with one another.
We have this one. So we have short risers, long risers
to build more tension throughout the video.
And sound effects is such a crucial part of any video.
If you like, you can take your video to a whole new level.
You can add another dimension to your video just
by doing some basic sound effects.
Like this is not too much
and it just elevates the video so much more.
And one last sound effect I was using was
this drone sound effect.
It can also be found in the sound effects pack by Azer X.
Yes. So I'm using this D base drone sound effect.
And, and for the text I'm just using a handwritten template.
And the background I found on Elements in Wato again,
and I'm using it basically to break down
between different sections of the trailer.
So I have one after the hook, I have one
after the conflict.
And then I also use some Zooms in throughout the trailer.
So I've just this adjustment clip with the transform effect.
And I put the scale to one 20 to zoom it a little bit.
And I also did this because I cut the video here.
And if, uh, if you watch it without the scale,
without the zoom, as you can see, like it's really jarring
to watch because she jumps instantly with the Zoom,
you don't notice it as much.
So if I enable it again,
it seems more seamless, I feel like.
And then I'm using a lot of B-roll from from film Pack.
Film Pack is a great website for to find B-roll.
The best thing about film pack is you can find B-roll.
Like you can find 50 shots of the same actor at the same set
with different camera angles,
with different camera movements.
So it looks really more professional.
It feels like you did all the production in-House rather
than sourcing random B roll from different websites.
The colors stay the same, the model stays the same
and it just flows so much better.
So I'm using a lot of B roll from film pack,
especially hair.
All of these shots are at the same set,
with the same actor, with the same camera.
The colors are the same and it just seems more
flawless and professional.
And I am also using Light Leaks transition by Mr. Horse.
This is in the free Mr Horse plugin.
And I'm using camera status at sound as sound effects.
So, and this is also in the Mr.
Horse plugin. It's free to use. So that's about it guys.
I went over my whole process on how I cut a trailer,
how I bring everything together,
how sound effects can make a really huge
impact on your video.
What does the structure look like in a trailer?
How do you put all the pieces together
to create a coherent story?
And I hope you guys enjoyed, thanks for watching guys,
and comment your thoughts in this thread.
I would love to know what everybody thinks.